# Mark Ernest R. Matute

148 Libo Balayong Malolos Bulacan +65 98315311 / +63975 8675463- markernest.matute@gmail.com

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-matute/

Github - <a href="https://github.com/MarkMatute">https://github.com/MarkMatute</a>

Portfolio - <a href="https://markmatute.github.io/">https://markmatute.github.io/</a>

#### **PROFILE**

Experienced Software Engineer working with latest technologies with JavaScript, PHP etc. Developing software applications with reliability, security and maintainability in mind both Front-end and Back-end applications. Advocate of TDD approach clean and simple code development.

#### **S**KILLS

- Back-End / API Development, JavaScript, TypeScript, TypeORM, NodeJS, REST, ExpressJS, Koa, Loopback, PHP, CodeIgniter
- CLI Development with NodeJS, Commander and Inquirer
- Front-End Development, ReactJS, Redux, AngularJS, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML
- API Stress Testing and reporting with JMeter
- Unit testing with Mocha and Chai
- Experienced with GIT and Agile Development(JIRA)
- Experienced in server configuration with Apache, Nginx, CentOS
- Databases, MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres
- Objective-C, Java

#### EXPERIENCE

## iHealth Labs Pte. Ltd.

Singapore

Software Engineer

March 2018 – present

- Develop API's using NodeJS, TypeScript, TypeORM, Koa, MongoDB and MySQL
- Developed Unit Testing Framework for the MILO Project using TypeScript, Mocha and Chai
- Developed Front-end features using React and Redux
- Developed CLI Tools to automate various tasks using NodeJS and TypeScript

## **EACOMM Corporation (Parti Time)**

Manila, Philippines

PHP Consultant

November 2017 – March 2018

- Develop and design PHP powered projects with CodeIgniter
- Manage End to End Development upto deployment of PHP Projects
- Maintenance works for the servers

**ISBX Inc.** Manila, Philippines

Full-Stack Web And Mobile Developer

June 2017 - February 2018

- Develop REST API's using NodeJS, LoopbackJS, MongoDB, MySQL
- Develop Front-end applications using AngularJS and Bootstrap
- Implemented API Stress testing and reporting using JMeter
- Develop iOS Applications using Objective-C

### **EACOMM Corporation**

Manila, Philippines

Software Developer

May 2016 – June 2017

- Develop and design PHP powered projects with CodeIgniter and WordPress
- Introduced usage of MVC for application development with PHP
- Develop and design REST API's with NodeJS and Java
- Maintenance works for the servers

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bulacan State University**

Philippines

BS Information Technology

Graduated Dean's Lister

### **Holy Spirit Academy of Malolos**

Philippines

Secondary Education

### **Holy Spirit Academy of Malolos**

**Philippines** 

Elementary Education